<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Strange Labs</title>
    <link>https://strangelabs.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Strange Labs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://strangelabs.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Strange Labs in the COVID Pandemic 2020</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/strange-labs-in-the-pandemic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/strange-labs-in-the-pandemic/</guid>
      <description>What happened to the shop?! Way back in December 2019, which now seems like an age ago, Strange Labs had made a decision to change direction from general PC repairs and upgrades to focus on building custom desktop PCs and web development work.
Why is this?
Well although we were doing brilliantly at our repairs and upgrades, our plan the whole time since we started in 2017 was to make a new type of technology shop - one which brought technology enthusiasts together to work on technology projects and investigate all sorts of emerging technologies on the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/helloworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/helloworld/</guid>
      <description>Hello world Welcome to Strange Labs blog. Below are the archived posts which have been imported from my previous websites. Writing blog posts is a weird thing to do. They can be a mixture of essays, considered and referenced, or they can be rambling thoughts like that in a personal diary. Strange Labs encorporates all, and excludes none. Posts may be revisted many times, edited and updated - such is the beauty of the digital copy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arguing for Open Source</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/arguing-for-open-source-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/arguing-for-open-source-code/</guid>
      <description>What is open source? Open source in it&amp;rsquo;s most literal definition is software in which the source code (ie. the instruction set which describes the functions that make it) is freely available to view, edit and then redistribute. Most software that you, as a general PC user, would use (Microsoft Windows, games, Adobe programs etc) are closed source. And for a pretty obvious reason!
The digital world is not quite the same as the physical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beginners Guide to Windows 10</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/guides/beginners-guide-to-windows-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/guides/beginners-guide-to-windows-10/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I have been asked many times for some help in getting started and achieving a basic understanding of the Windows 10 operating system (OS). Windows 10 came out on the 29th July 2015 but still people have some trouble finding their way around. This is, by definition, the result of substandard user experience and not necessarily Windows user’s own fault for not getting it. Of course a basic understanding of any computer system will help, but Windows 10 doesn’t make it as easy as it could be thanks to layers of abstraction built on what is essentially a combination of previous Windows versions underneath.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BSOD scams on windows 10</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/bsod-scams-on-windows-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/bsod-scams-on-windows-10/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve been using Windows for a long time, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard of or witnessed the infamous Blue Screen of Death, or BSOD for short.
It was a problem that set windows apart from other OS&amp;rsquo;s in the tech fail arena, and even occurred on a live demo by Bill Gates himself of Windows 98
Since then it has become a symbol of the ultimate computer error and has been picked up by many scam artists to try and shock unsuspecting Windows users into thinking something awful has happened to their PC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code, data and understanding each other</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/colour-and-understanding/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/colour-and-understanding/</guid>
      <description>What colour is that? Is the &amp;ldquo;red&amp;rdquo; colour I see, the same as the &amp;ldquo;red&amp;rdquo; colour you see? I believe anyone that has stopped to think about question this deeply will have started to have their existence unravelled. It is a question explored in this video by VSauce.
Red is the name of the colour we know in our language and culture. If you mix red with a little bit of white you would get what we call pink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing a space for technology enthusiasts</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/designing-a-space-for-technology-enthusiasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/designing-a-space-for-technology-enthusiasts/</guid>
      <description>Hello world We are half way through a refurbishment in store. So far, the first half has been very successful I would say, both in it&amp;rsquo;s own aesthetic, and how it reflects the computer enthusiasm nature of the space. How do we go about designing for this type of space? Especially if we are on a budget and thus have a view to refurbish the store as organically as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EGX Rezzed 2019 - Our most interesting picks!</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/egx-rezzed-2019-best-of-the-bunch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/egx-rezzed-2019-best-of-the-bunch/</guid>
      <description>EGX Rezzed, London’s biggest gaming event, concluded a week ago. Strange Labs was in attendance and amongst the various qualities of cosplayers wandering around, excellent merchandise and endless games to play, there were also some pretty cool talks from the developers themselves. We managed to get to a few (annoyingly everything inevitably overlaps at these sorts of events) and thought we would share our favourite picks of brand new, up and coming games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ever wondered about desktop backgrounds?</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/ever-wondered-about-desktop-backgrounds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/ever-wondered-about-desktop-backgrounds/</guid>
      <description>Windows 10 When I first upgraded a PC to Windows 10 many years ago, I was greeted with the new Windows desktop wallpaper. Pretty cool, I thought. A sort of futuristic Windows icon made out of light at a 3 dimensional angle in neon blues.
I never really considered it much more than that, and assumed CGI had created it.
However, that is not true! It actually is a digital composition of the analogue work by renowned artist-technologist GMUNK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evil Genius Gaming Tales</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/evil-genius-gaming-tales/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/evil-genius-gaming-tales/</guid>
      <description>How you play a game in the privacy of your own home, or the anonymity behind the monitor can say a lot about who you are and what you are like. Sometimes examples of gaming strategies reveal a utilitarian genius which is fascinating to me for two reasons: The ability to &amp;ldquo;win&amp;rdquo; the game in terms of an undesigned hack. And the reflection of the gamers psychology that the gaming strategy may be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forgotten your Windows 7 password?</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/guides/forgotten-your-windows-password/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/guides/forgotten-your-windows-password/</guid>
      <description>It is every Windows users nightmare: one day you try to log in and every attempt is denied. Whether you have forgotten your password or it has been changed or you need to get in and don&amp;rsquo;t have the password, there is a way to break in.
The Backdoor Take the battery out if you have a laptop and plug in the mains
Start windows and then whilst it is starting up, pull the power out to force an automatic startup repair on the next boot</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Stack Buildings Design</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/full-stack-buildings-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/full-stack-buildings-design/</guid>
      <description>We have seen a transition from top of the pyramid &amp;ldquo;architect&amp;rdquo; to a more inclusive &amp;ldquo;archtect-planner&amp;rdquo;, a move which requires a greater level of understanding laterally: in a buildings context. And, we are in that same evolution in the software version of the architect too.
What is “Full Stack”? In the world of computer science, and specifically web program development, there is a debate currently engaging the community. It began with the converging of ‘devs’ (developers): people writing programs, and ‘ops’ (operations): people who focus on how those programs run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to avoid the bait and not get phished!</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/dont-get-phished/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/dont-get-phished/</guid>
      <description>Ways To Defend Yourself Against Phishing Attacks Phishing attacks are cyberattacks that rely on deception and manipulation to trick a victim into offering up sensitive information. Such attacks fall under the category of social engineering attacks, which exploit human behavior and mentality, making them harder to defend against. Nevertheless, there are several ways that you can use to protect against phishing attacks.
Install cybersecurity measures
Cybersecurity measures act as a preventive, detective, and responsive measures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to think in the world of cyber crime</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/how-to-think-in-the-world-of-cyber-crime/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/how-to-think-in-the-world-of-cyber-crime/</guid>
      <description>It seems over the last few years we are increasingly frequently being informed of this cyber attack,that ransomwareinfection, this data leak&amp;hellip; To me it does make sense that these events would increase. If technological development follows Moore&amp;rsquo;s Law, then the events surrounding technology should also increase in frequency and impact at a cumulative rate.
And this is what appears to be happening. Cyber threat is increasing, computing is becoming more abstracted away from the binary that drives it, chips and data processing is becoming ubiquitous in our environments and lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imagining with Deep Dream</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/imagining-with-deep-dream/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/imagining-with-deep-dream/</guid>
      <description>I think I am late to the party here, but better late than never! I read the recently released white paper by Google: PathNet: Evolution Channels Gradient Descent in Super Neural Networksand became fascinated on the conceptual simplicity of the underpinning algorithms which build narrow artificial intelligence.
These methods are teaching Google and others to recognise and interpret images to aid searching, indexing, autonomous driving and many other activities. A quick and easy to understand explanation of the fundamental workings of the algorithm&amp;rsquo;s pattern composition network can be seen in the excellent Computerphile video here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting Hacks on your PC or Mac</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/interesting-hacks-on-your-pc-or-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/interesting-hacks-on-your-pc-or-mac/</guid>
      <description>Activate GOD MODE in Windows God mode has been a &amp;ldquo;feature&amp;rdquo; of Windows since 7 and has remained throughout to our current Windows 10. It is essentially a collection of every setting for your computer in a single folder on the Desktop labelled God Mode. To activate it, first you need to be an Administrator, so check that you are in Settings/Control Panel. Then do the following:
  Create a new folder on the desktop by right clicking anywhere on the desktop and go to new -&amp;gt; Folder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is data worth storing?</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/is-data-worth-storing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/is-data-worth-storing/</guid>
      <description>I recently read an article on Tediumlinked from hacker news about disc rot. It reminded me of two times in my past:
The first was after a hard drive I had failed. It was working fine and I put it down for a few months. One day I plugged it back in to find it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t mount. I spent some time on command line trying to force its mount and eventually discovered significant sector errors and a totally corrupt boot manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Louqe Ghost S1 - Case Review</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/louqe-ghost-s1-case-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/louqe-ghost-s1-case-review/</guid>
      <description>We’ve always had a thing for small PCs. The ITX form factor is just so cute and compact and there are some really cool ITX cases to play with. The Strange Labs every day use PC is in a Bitfenix Portalwhich is still one of more interesting looking cases out there. So when the opportunity came to build a SFF gaming PC in the new Louqe Ghost S1 we had to do it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sick of Windows 10? Try Linux!</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/guides/sick-of-windows-10-try-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/guides/sick-of-windows-10-try-linux/</guid>
      <description>Since Windows 10 free upgrade, our customers have complained about the sneaky tactics used by Microsoft to install their latest OS. They&amp;rsquo;ve complained about further updates breaking their systems. They&amp;rsquo;ve complained about the lack of various driver support for wifi, printers, bluetooth and more in Windows 10. They&amp;rsquo;ve complained about the abstracted ways to use the PC becoming confusing and unnecessary! It doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like Windows 10 is winning many hearts!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speeding up Windows 10 startup</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/guides/speeding-up-windows-10-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/guides/speeding-up-windows-10-startup/</guid>
      <description>Hardware So the first and easiest method (though unfortunately most expensive) is to upgrade the hardware. Adding a Solid State Drive (SSD) will greatly speed up the load times of Windows and all programs and files. An SSD has no moving parts, unlike traditional mechanical Hard Disk Drives and the read and write times are ten fold faster. NVMe SSDs are faster still as they no longer use the slower SATA protocol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strengthening relationships weakened by the internet</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/strengthening-relationships-weakened-by-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/strengthening-relationships-weakened-by-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>Introduction When I was a teenager, I rebelled against the mobile phone. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what it was about it but I just didn&amp;rsquo;t want one. Without really thinking too much about it then, I believe I foresaw a future of increasing social connections and as a result, imagined each connection becoming weaker. It may have been a bit of that, but it was definitely a bit of relunctance to being able to be contacted 24/7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting keyboard and mouse issues on Windows 10</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/guides/how-to-troubleshoot-keyboard-and-touchpad-issues-on-windows-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/guides/how-to-troubleshoot-keyboard-and-touchpad-issues-on-windows-10/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE - If your cursor is working, no need to edit the mouse settings. If your keyboard is working, no need to edit your keyboard settings. Just follow the steps for the device(s) which are not working.
Windows 10 isn&amp;rsquo;t the most robust Operating System out there. Often, the updates can break the computer in some way or another. They can clash with manufacturer updates, specifically they can attempt to replace the drivers installed by manufacturers with their own versions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terms and Conditions</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/terms/</guid>
      <description>Strange Labs Strange Labs is the trading name of Connor Alexander. It is now a solely online retailer and does not have a physical store.
Shipping &amp;amp; Returns Policy Strange Labs currently only sells and ships to customers that are located within the United Kingdom. The services provided by our carrier are outside our control. While we cannot guarantee delivery dates or times, UK delivery is normally no more than 1-2 working days after dispatch.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>