<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Strange Labs Computers</title>
    <link>https://strangelabs.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Strange Labs Computers</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://strangelabs.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Reforming Governance Is The Most Important Thing</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/why-reforming-governance-is-the-most-important-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/why-reforming-governance-is-the-most-important-thing/</guid>
      <description>Introduction How can we as a population effectively address matters of public concern that impact society, the economy, and the environment on local and global scales? How can we drive positive change in these areas?&#xA;While education may not solve many immediate problems it can be argued that education is most crucial as it ultimately addresses issues like these at their source over the long term. Education empowers an individual to make rational, logical and moral decisions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Future-Proofing Governance</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/futureproofing-governance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/futureproofing-governance/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Imagine designing a country&amp;rsquo;s system of governance from the ground up, leveraging all available technological resources and integrating lessons learned from history. How would such a system function? What principles would guide its operations?&#xA;Future-proof is a think-tank dedicated to exploring these questions and more. We do not profess to have definitive answers but aim to stimulate thoughtful discussion. Founded by technologists with expertise in software development and systems design, Futureproof aspires to build a diverse community of thinkers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How To Install Windows 11 Without A Microsoft Account</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/guides/installing-windows-11-without-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/guides/installing-windows-11-without-account/</guid>
      <description>Introduction When setting up a fresh install of Windows 11, you&amp;rsquo;re prompted to log in with a Microsoft account by default. While this integration offers various benefits, such as seamless access to OneDrive and syncing settings across devices, many users prefer the privacy and control of a local account. However, Microsoft strongly encourages, to the point of forcing, the use of an online account during setup. In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the methods to bypass these attempts and successfully set up Windows 11 with a local account, ensuring you have the freedom and privacy you desire.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terms and Conditions</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/terms/</guid>
      <description>Strange Labs Computers Ltd Strange Labs Computers, strangelabs.io and other related content is owned by Strange Labs Computers Ltd. Strange Labs Computers Ltd is solely an online retailer and does not have a physical store.&#xA;Shipping &amp;amp; Returns Policy Strange Labs Computers Ltd currently only sells and ships to customers that are located within the United Kingdom. The services provided by our carrier are outside our control. While we cannot guarantee delivery dates or times, UK delivery is normally no more than 1-2 working days after dispatch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parting with Your Computer- Is Your Data Safe?</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/guides/is-my-data-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/guides/is-my-data-safe/</guid>
      <description>Introduction At some point, you may need to part with your computer. Whether it’s a company-owned machine that needs to be returned, or you’re selling it to upgrade to a new model, one thing is certain—it contains a lot of your personal data. Some of that data is likely quite sensitive.&#xA;Imagine if someone gained access to your photos, addresses, documents, passwords, or financial information. The potential consequences are alarming: identity theft, unauthorized purchases, fraudulent loans, ransomware attacks, or even blackmail.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genius Gaming Tales</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/wip/genius-gaming-tales/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/wip/genius-gaming-tales/</guid>
      <description>Gaming is great, but what&amp;rsquo;s really great is when you devise a plan to &amp;ldquo;hack&amp;rdquo; the game using nothing but the engine itself, No cheats, no actually hacking, just working out a genius plan.&#xA;How you play a game in the privacy of your own home, or the anonymity behind the monitor can say a lot about who you are and what you are like. Sometimes examples of gaming strategies reveal a utilitarian genius which is fascinating to me for two reasons: The ability to &amp;ldquo;win&amp;rdquo; the game in terms of exploiting an undesigned hack.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diagnosing Internet Issues On Windows 10</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/guides/diagnosing-internet-issues-win-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/guides/diagnosing-internet-issues-win-10/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In today&amp;rsquo;s world, the internet is essential for daily life. It&amp;rsquo;s so integral to our society that the UN has declared internet access a human right. We rely on it for work, entertainment, socializing, and research, so when a slow, intermittent, or non-existent connection disrupts our access, it can be incredibly frustrating. Fortunately, Strange Labs has some solutions to help you get back online!&#xA;Is it the router or the PC?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Easily replace your boot drive on any computer without losing data.</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/guides/replace-your-boot-drive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/guides/replace-your-boot-drive/</guid>
      <description>Introduction If you have run out of space on your boot drive, using your PC can become quite restrictive and irritating. You might not be able to save files, or even open programs or the internet if there is no space left. If this happens you have a couple of options to get more space: the easiest being adding another hard drive or solid state drive. However this may not be an option for you, or you may need or want to replace your drive with a bigger one!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Art Behind Default OS Wallpapers</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/the-art-behind-default-os-wallpapers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/the-art-behind-default-os-wallpapers/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Backgrounds are often the unsung heroes of our digital experience. Whether it’s the calming landscape of a rolling hill or a futuristic light display, these images are seen by millions every day, yet rarely given the recognition they deserve. Let’s take a moment to spotlight some of the most iconic background images that have come pre-packaged with operating systems over the years, celebrating the artistry and thought that went into creating them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How To Think In A World Of Cybercrime</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/how-to-think-in-a-world-of-cybercrime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/how-to-think-in-a-world-of-cybercrime/</guid>
      <description>Introduction As technology and networking become increasingly integrated into our lives, the threat of cybercrime will only grow. It&amp;rsquo;s a scary reality, and if you find yourself feeling paranoid, you&amp;rsquo;re probably justified. In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll share how I approach this complex digital landscape and offer some advice on how you might want to think about it too. Be warned, though—this perspective isn&amp;rsquo;t for the faint of heart.&#xA;The Escalating Cyber Threat In recent years, we’ve been bombarded with news about cyber attacks, ransomware infections, and data breaches.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Data Worth Storing?</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/is-data-worth-storing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/is-data-worth-storing/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The storage and preservation of digital data have become critical concerns in an age where information is increasingly digitized. A Tedium article on disc rot prompted a reflection on two personal experiences related to data loss and long-term storage, leading to profound questions about the feasibility and necessity of preserving digital data indefinitely. This post explores the complexities of long-term data storage, considers the implications of evolving file types, and delves into the philosophical question of whether all data should be preserved.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strange Labs Build Process</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/how-we-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/how-we-work/</guid>
      <description>Ordering a PC with Strange Labs Computers Ordering a PC with Strange Labs is a simple, but personal service. We work hand in hand with you to create your perfect PC. This means, rather than offering off the shelf configurations, we tailor your PC using current, highly rated and specifically chosen components.&#xA;Computer Specification Beginning the specification process starts by completing the order form. We encourage you to fill this out with as much detail as possible, especially on what you would like to get out of your PC.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beginners Guide To Windows 10</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/guides/beginners-guide-to-windows-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/guides/beginners-guide-to-windows-10/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I have been asked many times for some help in getting started and achieving a basic understanding of the Windows 10 operating system (OS). Windows 10 came out on the 29th July 2015 but still people have some trouble finding their way around. This is, by definition, the result of substandard user experience and not necessarily Windows user’s own fault for not getting it. Of course a basic understanding of any computer system will help, but Windows 10 doesn’t make it as easy as it could be thanks to layers of abstraction built on what is essentially a combination of previous Windows versions underneath.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interesting Easter Eggs on your PC or Mac</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/wip/interesting-hacks-on-your-pc-or-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/wip/interesting-hacks-on-your-pc-or-mac/</guid>
      <description>Why not spend a little time playing about with some interesting and cool hacks we have found for you to try :)&#xA;Activate GOD MODE in Windows God mode has been a &amp;ldquo;feature&amp;rdquo; of Windows since 7 and has remained throughout to our current Windows 10. It is essentially a collection of every setting for your computer in a single folder on the Desktop labelled God Mode. To activate it, first you need to be an Administrator, so check that you are in Settings/Control Panel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strengthening Relationships Weakened By The Internet</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/wip/strengthening-relationships-weakened-by-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/wip/strengthening-relationships-weakened-by-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>Last updated: August 2024&#xA;Introduction When I was a teenager, at around 2003, I rebelled against the mobile phone. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what it was about it but I just didn&amp;rsquo;t want one. Without really thinking too much about it then, I believe I foresaw a future of increasing social connections and as a result, imagined each connection becoming weaker. It may have been a bit of that, but it was definitely a bit of relunctance to being able to be contacted 24/7.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sick of Windows 10? Try Linux!</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/guides/sick-of-windows-10-try-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/guides/sick-of-windows-10-try-linux/</guid>
      <description>Since Windows 10 free upgrade, our customers have complained about the sneaky tactics used by Microsoft to install their latest OS. They&amp;rsquo;ve complained about further updates breaking their systems. They&amp;rsquo;ve complained about the lack of various driver support for wifi, printers, bluetooth and more in Windows 10. They&amp;rsquo;ve complained about the abstracted ways to use the PC becoming confusing and unnecessary! It doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like Windows 10 is winning many hearts!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How To Avoid The Bait And Not Get Phished</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/guides/how-to-avoid-the-bait-and-not-get-phished/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/guides/how-to-avoid-the-bait-and-not-get-phished/</guid>
      <description>Introduction One of the most common way to get scammed or hacked is through a method called “Phishing”. It is very easy to fall foul of this type of con and can result in loss of control over your data and identity to the hackers. The following is a guest article by Techwarn which goes some way to help you avoid this sort of attack and educate yourselves in this method of cybercrime.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EGX Rezzed 2019 - Our most interesting picks!</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/wip/egx-rezzed-2019-best-of-the-bunch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/wip/egx-rezzed-2019-best-of-the-bunch/</guid>
      <description>EGX Rezzed, London’s biggest gaming event, concluded a week ago. Strange Labs was in attendance and amongst the various qualities of cosplayers wandering around, excellent merchandise and endless games to play, there were also some pretty cool talks from the developers themselves. We managed to get to a few (annoyingly everything inevitably overlaps at these sorts of events) and thought we would share our favourite picks of brand new, up and coming games.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing A Space For Technology Enthusiasts</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/designing-a-space-for-technology-enthusiasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/designing-a-space-for-technology-enthusiasts/</guid>
      <description>Introduction From 2017 to 2020, I embarked on an exciting project to transform my traditional PC repair shop into a dynamic social space where programmers could meet, collaborate, and work on projects. Midway through this transformation, I shared an update on the progress. Now, as we close the chapter on this journey, I’m reflecting on the design process and what we achieved. For the final look before closing, be sure to check out the photos at the end.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speeding up Windows 10 startup</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/guides/speeding-up-windows-10-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/guides/speeding-up-windows-10-startup/</guid>
      <description>Hardware So the first and easiest method (though unfortunately most expensive) is to upgrade the hardware. Adding a Solid State Drive (SSD) will greatly speed up the load times of Windows and all programs and files. An SSD has no moving parts, unlike traditional mechanical Hard Disk Drives and the read and write times are ten fold faster. NVMe SSDs are faster still as they no longer use the slower SATA protocol.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BSOD scams on windows 10</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/wip/bsod-scams-on-windows-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/wip/bsod-scams-on-windows-10/</guid>
      <description>Getting scammed is a growing threat in our connected world. Here are a couple of old BSOD examples that try to scare you into giving away control or money.&#xA;If you&amp;rsquo;ve been using Windows for a long time, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard of or witnessed the infamous Blue Screen of Death, or BSOD for short.&#xA;It was a problem that set windows apart from other OS&amp;rsquo;s in the tech fail arena, and even occurred on a live demo by Bill Gates himself of Windows 98</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting keyboard and mouse issues with laptops on Windows 10</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/guides/how-to-troubleshoot-keyboard-and-touchpad-issues-on-windows-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/guides/how-to-troubleshoot-keyboard-and-touchpad-issues-on-windows-10/</guid>
      <description>Windows 10 isn&amp;rsquo;t the most robust Operating System out there. Often, the updates can break the computer in some way or another. They can clash with manufacturer updates, specifically they can attempt to replace the drivers installed by manufacturers with their own versions. Wi-Fi, optical drives and other devices can be affected, but today we will cover the keyboard and mouse - probably the most irritating of devices to fail on your laptop!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Code, Data And Understanding Each Other In A Digital World</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/code-data-and-understanding-each-other/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/code-data-and-understanding-each-other/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Our understanding of one another can only ever approximate true comprehension. We cannot inhabit each other&amp;rsquo;s consciousness to experience the world as the other does. Knowing that no one will ever truly understand you, how does that influence your experiences? We must dedicate time to learning each other&amp;rsquo;s stories and remain open-minded to align our understanding as closely as possible. This is already a challenge in our physical lives, but what happens in the digital realm?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Louqe Ghost S1 - Case Review</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/wip/louqe-ghost-s1-case-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/wip/louqe-ghost-s1-case-review/</guid>
      <description>The Loque Ghost S1 is a superb piece of design for building the smallest possible ITX build by volume whilst maintaining great airflow and temperatures. This is our customer build transferring their original PC into the new case.&#xA;We’ve always had a thing for small PCs. The ITX form factor is just so cute and compact and there are some really cool ITX cases to play with. The Strange Labs every day use PC is in a Bitfenix Portal which is still one of more interesting looking cases out there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Imagining with Deep Dream</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/wip/imagining-with-deep-dream/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/wip/imagining-with-deep-dream/</guid>
      <description>Google&amp;rsquo;s Deep Dream shows us how simple pattern play in visuals, with some iterative dynamics, can create experiences which previously felt exclusively human, spiritual and deeply conscious. This reinforces the idea of our mind as a complex network of networks and ultimately recreatable by technology.&#xA;I think I am late to the party here, but better late than never! I read the recently released white paper by Google: PathNet: Evolution Channels Gradient Descent in Super Neural Networks and became fascinated on the conceptual simplicity of the underpinning algorithms which build narrow artificial intelligence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forgotten your Windows 7 password?</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/guides/forgotten-your-windows-password/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/guides/forgotten-your-windows-password/</guid>
      <description>It is every Windows users nightmare: one day you try to log in and every attempt is denied. Whether you have forgotten your password or it has been changed or you need to get in and don&amp;rsquo;t have the password, there is a way to break in.&#xA;The Backdoor Take the battery out if you have a laptop and plug in the mains&#xA;Start windows and then whilst it is starting up, pull the power out to force an automatic startup repair on the next boot.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arguing For Open Source</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/arguing-for-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/arguing-for-open-source/</guid>
      <description>Why Should We Trust What People Hide from Us? Open source technology holds the potential to build greater trust among people. By extending the principles of open source from computer science to other areas of society and culture, we might unlock significant benefits.&#xA;What is open source? At its core, open source refers to software whose source code—the underlying instructions that define how the software functions—is freely available for anyone to view, modify, and redistribute.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Full Stack Buildings Design</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/full-stack-buildings-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/full-stack-buildings-design/</guid>
      <description>Designing Buildings in the Future The future of architecture is evolving, giving rise to a new breed of architects with broader vision, deeper influence, and a more comprehensive understanding of their craft. These future architects won’t just design buildings in the traditional sense—from material selection to philosophical considerations—but will also grasp the intricacies of modern technology. They will understand everything from the flow of electrons in wiring to the connectivity of the internet, and how these elements interact with the building&amp;rsquo;s users in an increasingly digital world.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
