<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>design on Strange Labs Computers</title>
    <link>https://strangelabs.io/tags/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in design on Strange Labs Computers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://strangelabs.io/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ever wondered about desktop backgrounds?</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/ever-wondered-about-desktop-backgrounds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/ever-wondered-about-desktop-backgrounds/</guid>
      <description>Backgrounds are often taken for granted. At least the ones that come pre-shipped with new computers. We take a look at iconic background images that come pre-packaged with operating systems over the years. Let&amp;rsquo;s put them into the spotlight like they deserve!
Windows Windows 10 When I first upgraded a PC to Windows 10 many years ago, I was greeted with the new Windows desktop wallpaper. Pretty cool, I thought. A sort of futuristic Windows icon made out of light at a 3 dimensional angle in neon blues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing a space for technology enthusiasts</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/designing-a-space-for-technology-enthusiasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/designing-a-space-for-technology-enthusiasts/</guid>
      <description>From 2017 to 2020, I had a physical shop, the idea was to convert it from a boring PC repair shop into a social space where programmers could meet to work on projects. This was a post made part way through that development. For the last pics before I closed, go to the end
We are half way through a refurbishment in store. So far, the first half has been very successful I would say, both in it&amp;rsquo;s own aesthetic, and how it reflects the computer enthusiasm nature of the space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Louqe Ghost S1 - Case Review</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/louqe-ghost-s1-case-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/louqe-ghost-s1-case-review/</guid>
      <description>The Loque Ghost S1 is a superb piece of design for building the smallest possible ITX build by volume whilst maintaining great airflow and temperatures. This is our customer build transferring their original PC into the new case.
We’ve always had a thing for small PCs. The ITX form factor is just so cute and compact and there are some really cool ITX cases to play with. The Strange Labs every day use PC is in a Bitfenix Portal which is still one of more interesting looking cases out there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imagining with Deep Dream</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/imagining-with-deep-dream/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/imagining-with-deep-dream/</guid>
      <description>Google&amp;rsquo;s Deep Dream shows us how simple pattern play in visuals, with some iterative dynamics, can create experiences which previously felt exclusively human, spiritual and deeply conscious. This reinforces the idea of our mind as a complex network of networks and ultimately recreatable by technology.
I think I am late to the party here, but better late than never! I read the recently released white paper by Google: PathNet: Evolution Channels Gradient Descent in Super Neural Networks and became fascinated on the conceptual simplicity of the underpinning algorithms which build narrow artificial intelligence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Stack Buildings Design</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/full-stack-buildings-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/full-stack-buildings-design/</guid>
      <description>Designing Buildings in the Future A new type of architect is coming. One with greater vision, greater influence and greater understanding. This architect of the future understands the building they will design not only from the material to the philosophy in the traditional sense, but from the electron in the wiring to the connectivity of the internet and the languages to converse these layers to the building user as part of a new, technological world.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>