<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hardware on Strange Labs Computers</title>
    <link>https://strangelabs.io/tags/hardware/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hardware on Strange Labs Computers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://strangelabs.io/tags/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Easily replace your boot drive on any computer without losing data.</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/guides/replace-your-boot-drive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/guides/replace-your-boot-drive/</guid>
      <description>Introduction If you have run out of space on your boot drive, using your PC can become quite restrictive and irritating. You might not be able to save files, or even open programs or the internet if there is no space left. If this happens you have a couple of options to get more space: the easiest being adding another hard drive or solid state drive. However this may not be an option for you, or you may need or want to replace your drive with a bigger one!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speeding up Windows 10 startup</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/guides/speeding-up-windows-10-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/guides/speeding-up-windows-10-startup/</guid>
      <description>Hardware So the first and easiest method (though unfortunately most expensive) is to upgrade the hardware. Adding a Solid State Drive (SSD) will greatly speed up the load times of Windows and all programs and files. An SSD has no moving parts, unlike traditional mechanical Hard Disk Drives and the read and write times are ten fold faster. NVMe SSDs are faster still as they no longer use the slower SATA protocol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Louqe Ghost S1 - Case Review</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/louqe-ghost-s1-case-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/louqe-ghost-s1-case-review/</guid>
      <description>The Loque Ghost S1 is a superb piece of design for building the smallest possible ITX build by volume whilst maintaining great airflow and temperatures. This is our customer build transferring their original PC into the new case.
We’ve always had a thing for small PCs. The ITX form factor is just so cute and compact and there are some really cool ITX cases to play with. The Strange Labs every day use PC is in a Bitfenix Portal which is still one of more interesting looking cases out there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Stack Buildings Design</title>
      <link>https://strangelabs.io/blog/full-stack-buildings-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strangelabs.io/blog/full-stack-buildings-design/</guid>
      <description>Designing Buildings in the Future A new type of architect is coming. One with greater vision, greater influence and greater understanding. This architect of the future understands the building they will design not only from the material to the philosophy in the traditional sense, but from the electron in the wiring to the connectivity of the internet and the languages to converse these layers to the building user as part of a new, technological world.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>